<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>security on Blog</title><link>https://blog.zhade.dev/tags/security/</link><description>Recent content in security on Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.zhade.dev/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How Reversible are Embeddings: Embedding Inversions and How to Protect your Data</title><link>https://blog.zhade.dev/posts/2025-10-28-embeddings-inversion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.zhade.dev/posts/2025-10-28-embeddings-inversion/</guid><description>I was recently asked to determine the sensitivity of embeddings generated from proprietary code. While it seemed natural to think that embeddings were one-way functions that could not be reversed, research revealed that substantial semantic leakage was possible—even if direct reconstruction was not.
Embeddings turn a token—a word, subword, or symbol— into a vector that encodes its semantic meaning. However, these vectors are not unique; multiple tokens can map to the same vector, and as such are a lossy function.</description></item><item><title>Prompt Injection is a Weakness, not a Vulnerability</title><link>https://blog.zhade.dev/posts/2025-05-15-prompt-injection-weakness/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.zhade.dev/posts/2025-05-15-prompt-injection-weakness/</guid><description>Prompt injection is the most widely discussed emergent threat for Large Language Models (LLMs). But how should organizations approach tracking and prioritizing it?
In my opinion, instead of being a vulnerability in and of itself, prompt injection is a weakness that leads to other, more potent vulnerabilities. While it is true that prompt injection is undesirable, it doesn’t necessarily lead to any business value compromises and is also (at the time of writing) unsolvable.</description></item><item><title>Secure Generative UIs with Grammar Constrained Decoding</title><link>https://blog.zhade.dev/posts/2025-04-29-secure-generative-uis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.zhade.dev/posts/2025-04-29-secure-generative-uis/</guid><description>LLMs are very powerful for generating arbitrary text, but they really shine when you ask them to generate structured output. One such use case is generating rich UIs and text.
It’s much easier to read the output of an LLM if it’s properly styled and interactive. Reading large blobs of text can get unwieldy, and adding styling and interactive elements dynamically makes the output much more user-friendly and personalizable. This is known as a Generative UI; a User Interface that is generated in real-time by a generative AI.</description></item><item><title>Path to SOC Analyst: Breaking into Cybersecurity</title><link>https://blog.zhade.dev/posts/2025-02-23-path-to-soc-analyst/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.zhade.dev/posts/2025-02-23-path-to-soc-analyst/</guid><description>This was originally drafted as a Google doc for a friend.
If you’re trying to break into cybersecurity with no previous cyber, engineering, or IT experience, the best way to break into the industry is as a SOC analyst.
SOC Analysts are cybersecurity analysts responsible for monitoring corporate networks for potential threats and intrusions. While certainly not an introductory IT/ engineering role, it is the closest thing to an introductory role in security.</description></item><item><title>Setting Secure Hashing Parameters for Password Hashing</title><link>https://blog.zhade.dev/posts/2022-05-28-setting-secure-hashing-params/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.zhade.dev/posts/2022-05-28-setting-secure-hashing-params/</guid><description>TLDR: As of May 2022, I’d recommend using Argon2Id with the parameters recommended in RFC 9106
When trying to select the right way to protect your user’s passwords and credentials, there’s two things we need to consider. Firstly, we need to choose the right algorithm, one that is cryptographically secure. Secondly, we need to se the right parameters for the given algorithm to make it behave as securely as possible.</description></item></channel></rss>